<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-06T19:33:32-05:00</updated><id>https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/feed.xml</id><title type="html">fastpages</title><subtitle>An easy to use blogging platform with support for Jupyter Notebooks.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Code.org Blog Post</title><link href="https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/markdown/2022/09/05/Codeorg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Code.org Blog Post" /><published>2022-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/markdown/2022/09/05/Codeorg</id><author><name></name></author><category term="markdown" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Code.org blog post for AP CSA]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1 - Java Objects Post</title><link href="https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/jupyter/2022/08/31/GUI-menu.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1 - Java Objects Post" /><published>2022-08-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/jupyter/2022/08/31/GUI-menu</id><author><name>Dylan Luo</name></author><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blog post demonstrating Java objects for AP CSA]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Collegeboard Topics</title><link href="https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/2022/08/27/collegeboard-topics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Collegeboard Topics" /><published>2022-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/2022/08/27/collegeboard-topics</id><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Home AP Computer Science Principles A College Board Topics Unit 1: Primitive Types In Java, there are primitive and non-primitive data types. Some primitive data types include int, double and boolean, and some non-primitive data types include String and array. Data Types: int: Used for all integers. double: Used for numbers with decimals. boolean: Used for all boolean values, which are usually two return values that typically vary between true or false. String: Used for all text values. Java Input: "static" or "hard coded" programs typically when all of the website information is displayed by default. There are no instances of user input in these types of programs. To increase user interaction, having user inputs is important In Java, Scanner is the utility class used for console user input All programming has the means of formatting and combining data. An example of this is shown through concatenation (e.g. "Hello," + " World!" = "Hello, World!". The "+" symbol combined the two strings). Unit 2: Using Objects The relationship between a class and an object is that a class is essentially a template for an object, and an object is an instance of a class. Other College Board Topics related to this unit: A 2D array can be used to store colors. A control structure can be used to process menu selections. A switch can be used to run code that performs the related action of a selection. A 1D array can be used to hold a menu. A control structure such as if-else if-else can be used to process menu selections by running code that performs the related action of a selection. Class inheritance. Conditional statements, while loops, and boolean expressions. Some Java imports are designated toward allowing user input and console output in the terminal. The Scanner class makes an object to collect inputs / menu selections from users The System class can be used to call static methods like System.out.print() and System.out.println() to output in the console. The Math class can be used to call the static method Math.random() to generate a random number within a specified range. Objects are often intended to encapsulate Frontend, Backend, Web Site control flow, Database CRUD Operations, and many more. With Swing and AWT imports, Java has the ability to provide a Graphical User Interface (GUI) on the desktop. Unit 3: Boolean Expressions and If Statements Unit 4: Iteration Unit 5: Writing Classes Unit 6: Array Unit 7: ArrayList Unit 8: 2D Array Unit 9: Inheritance Unit 10: Recursion]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1 - Java Primitives Post</title><link href="https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/jupyter/2022/08/27/Java-Primitives.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1 - Java Primitives Post" /><published>2022-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/jupyter/2022/08/27/Java-Primitives</id><author><name>Dylan Luo</name></author><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Blog Post Demonstrating Java Primitives for AP CSA]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 1 - Bash Post</title><link href="https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/jupyter/2022/08/26/My-First-Bash.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 1 - Bash Post" /><published>2022-08-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-08-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://dylanluo05.github.io/DylanLuoAPCSA/jupyter/2022/08/26/My-First-Bash</id><author><name>Dylan Luo</name></author><category term="jupyter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bash Post Checking Installations for AP CSA]]></summary></entry></feed>